#### **MEHRAD MIRALI**

8<sup>th</sup> Daryano, Tehran, 1455955347 • 00989123407141 •

#### Mehrad.mirali@gmail.com

#### **Professional Summary**

Self motivated, global operations/ R&D, Manufacturing engineering and customer service with upwards of 10 years of experience working within consumer electronics industries, Presented history of serving in numerous level positions. Extensive strategic planning and implementing quality management system.

#### Core Competencies

Process & Quality Improvement. Manufacturing engineering.. Quality Management Systems implementation. Strategic planning. Customer Service operation management. Continuous improvement. CE Technical support.

#### **Skills**

- Team supervision
- autonomous
- Good multi task
- Data analysis
- Customer relationship building
- Disciplined

- Self- motivated
- Microsoft outlook, word and Excel
- Effective problem solver
- Skilled trainer
- sociable
- balanced

#### **Work History**

#### Service Controller (3/2020-current)

#### **ASUS**

- Play as single point of contact towards service partners for Service & Support.
- Control service partners activities to be aligned with company policies,
- Follow up with service partners in order to improve Customer Satisfaction.
- Day to day RMA and TAT control. To control the service quality and service partners performance daily basis by using daily dashboard reports.
- Following daily dashboard reports and notify service partners about TAT and repair quality.
- Follow up with compensation/ escalation and send the report to service manager.
- Reporting, analysis, benchmark. Audit service partners repair center, Warehouse and reception area based on weekly schedule and report the issues to service manager..

#### **Technical Instructor** (1/2013-current)

#### Samsung Engineering Academy-Tehran

- Designs, develops and delivers instructor-home appliances training courses on business-specific processes, products, systems or other initiatives. Evaluates student performance through written and hands-on assessments.
- Provides project support for training initiatives. Coordinates training projects from start to finish including tasks and timelines.
   Serves as subject matter expert for instructional designers, technical writers. Reviews instructional designs, testing procedures and technology.
- Populates system training or test regions with data for use in classes, provides client updates, analyzes data and writes training summaries.
- Maintains subject matter expertise for assigned business areas, including job shadowing, attending team meetings, process updates, staffing and providing production support as required.
- Engages instructional designers when significant edits are required (course redesigns). Designs and develops course content for narrowly focused topics.
- Builds team structure and increases team efficiency by contributing to internal processes and tools.

#### Field Operation Manager (02/2015 to12/2019)

#### beko(Mahestan)-Tehran

- Met with senior management to determine needs and develop road maps.
- Managed 100000\$ yearly budget covering service issues.
- Implemented marketing strategies which result in 10% growth of customer base.
- Oversaw the work of 10 personnel, with 3 direct reports.
- Monitored team performance to access training requirements and areas in need of requirements.
- Collaborated with call center to ensure smooth work flow and efficient organization operations.
- Consistently assumed additional responsibilities and worked extended hours to meet project deadlines.
- Maintained positive relationship with all customers.
- Report to factory about quality and epidemic issues.
- Resolved all customer complaints in professional manner while prioritizing customer satisfaction.
- Effectively communicated with supported sales, marketing and administrative teams on daily basis.
- Worked with management team to implement proper division of responsibilities.

#### Field Service supervisor (08/2012 to 02/2015)

#### Samsung (Samservice) - Tehran

- Led team of 100 service technicians in all home appliances.
- Monitored work performance and quality to maintain standards.
- Provided technical support for home appliances.
- Worked with suppliers to outline improvement strategies like KPI.
- Worked with support teams to resolve issues with product service or accounting.
- Trained, coached and mentored staff to ensure smooth adoption of new appliances.
- Collaborated with supply chain to ensure that the parts quantity was meeting daily and monthly projections and forecasts.
- Worked directly with customer satisfaction and CEO to achieve best result of satisfaction.

#### **Design Engineer** (08/2010 to 02/2012)

#### Sinjer - Tehran

- 2 years experience in identifying design requirements and developing solutions.
- Designed parts using injection molding techniques and assisted with the design of molds.
- Provided technical engineering support and project management for the design engineering and development of home appliances.
- Created CAD drawings to convey manufacturing and production configurations.
- Developed concept layout and design of home appliances from product specifications using 3D CAD software.
- Consulted with marketing department about product upgrades and failures in service.
- Continually improved methods and procedures for process, measurement, documenting and work techniques.

#### **Education**

**Bachelor of Science:** Mechanical engineering (2010)

Islamic Azad University

#### **Certifications**

- Master engineer of home appliances by Samsung electronics.
- Certificate of attendance in major domestic appliances training by beko.
- Certificate of attendance in major domestic appliances training by arcelik.
- Certificate of attendance in major domestic appliances training by Samsung.
- Training the trainers by industrial research & training center of Iran.

#### **Additional Information**

- Writing an education standard for Iran technical and vocational training organization (<a href="http://research.irantvto.ir/uploads/nasbe">http://research.irantvto.ir/uploads/nasbe</a> va tamir mashine haii zarfshoii.pdf)
- Working in Samsung engineering academy as a technical tutor of Dishwasher.

### WHAT MAKES MEHRAD UNIQUE?

ASSESSED BY RED BULL WINGFINDER, 27 APRIL 2019

Top strength:

#### DISCIPLINED

mehrad is driven to complete what he starts and likes his workflow to be structured with to-do lists and calendars. People can rely on him because he is efficient and cares about He succeeds through

- setting himself high standards
- planning ahead
- providing consistency



Can be relied on to deliver



Gets frustrated by tasks that don't have much structure



This strength is part of what DRIVES mehrad

mehrad's DRIVE result measures his level of ambition. He is confident and determined to produce work that is consistently excellent. A strong sense of competition motivates him, too. He values the respect of his superiors and enjoys being able to prove himself.

Top strength:

#### **SOCIABLE**

Social events are something mehrad is naturally good at. He prefers being around people and enjoys making new connections.

He succeeds through

- being comfortable around people
- being energised by spending time with others
- taking an interest in others



Thrives on meeting new people



Can find it hard to work alone

Top strength:

#### **AUTONOMOUS**

While able to work as part of a team, it's when mehrad is given the opportunity to think independently that he does his best work.

He succeeds through

- thinking for himself
- standing up for what he believes in
- focusing on own tasks and deliverables

(+)

Enjoys working independently



Can focus too much

Top strength:

#### **BALANCED**

mehrad is good at keeping a cool head, and staying upbeat and focused.

He succeeds through

- $\, {\rm his} \, \, {\rm confidence} \,$
- keeping positive
- not worrying too much

(+)

Stays calm when stress levels rise

<u>(!)</u>

May not realise when others are stressed



These strengths help explain the way mehrad works with other people — his CONNECTIONS

The CONNECTIONS result measures how mehrad manages relationships and how well he works independently. mehrad enjoys being at a stage in his career where he is helping other people, establishing connections and growing a network.



## Certificate of Attendance

This is to acknowledge that

Mr. Seyed Mehrad Mirali Gilak

has successfully completed the Training of Major Domestic Appliances.

Training Engineer
Mr. Eren TEKIN

4 th

Date

01-03 November 2017

Customer Services Director
Mr. Hüseyin Senf Beyoztar



**™Koc** 



## **Certificate of Attendance**

This Is To Acknowledge That

Mr. Seyed Mehrad Mirali Gilak

Has Successfully Completed The

**Training of Major Domestic Appliances** 

24 - 25 May 2016

Mr.Bülent UTKU
Technical Support and Training Manager

Mr. Hüseyin Şerif Beyaztaş Customer/Services Director





# Basic Level Technical Certificate Samsung Electronics



certifies that

Mr. Mehrad Mirali

#### SamService

has achieved Essential Skills and Technical Proficiencies in REF products and is awarded Master Engineer certificate for demonstrating knowledge and skills through overall performance assessment and analysis in accordance with industry requirements adopted by Samsung Electronics.

Certificate No.

Date Issued: 01.12.2014

Expiration Date: Three years from Date of Issue

Chang Jin Kang

Managing Director MENA CS HQ

Samsung Electronics



## Basic Level Technical Certificate Samsung Electronics



certifies that

Mehrad Mir Ali

Samservice, Iran

has achieved Essential Skills and Technical Proficiencies in HA products and is awarded Expert Engineer certificate for demonstrating knowledge and skills through overall performance assessment and analysis in accordance with industry requirements adopted by Samsung Electronics.

Certificate No. 131031-HA

Date Issued: 31st October 2013

Certificate Expiration: One Year from Date of Issue

Chang Jin Kang

Managing Director MENA CS HQ Samsung Electronics